Guide to the Panhellenic Council records, 1940-1970.
Panhellenic Council records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Panhellenic Council records, 1940-1970.
37-4-1545
Panhellenic Council.
3 cubic ft.
Correspondence, financial documents, printed material, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes circular letters; sorority financial reports, questionnaires, and statistics; rushing booklets, questionnaires, infractions, house statistics, finances, historical material, and other records; descriptions of sororities; correspondence and other papers related to individual fraternities and sororities at Cornell University; Panhellenic rules; and material on the National Panhellenic Council.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes circular letters; sorority financial reports, questionnaires, and statistics; rushing booklets, questionnaires, infractions, house statistics, finances, historical material, and other records; descriptions of sororities; correspondence and other papers related to individual fraternities and sororities at Cornell University; Panhellenic rules; and material on the National Panhellenic Council.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Panhellenic Council.; City of Ithaca Panhellenic Council.; Cornell University -- Societies, etc.; Cornell University. Panhellenic Council.; National Panhellenic Council.
Subjects:
Greek letter societies.
Form and Genre Terms:
Questionnaires.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Documents for Specific Greek Organizations
Housemother Manuals
Series II. General Panhellenic Council Papers
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Documents for Specific Greek Organizations
  - Kappa Alpha Theta Fund, 1960s, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Phi Delta Gamma Documents (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kappa Delta Documents (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Phi Sigma Sigma Documents (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Iota Alpha Pi (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alpha Epsilon P. Documents Documents (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alpha Xi Delta Documents (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alpha Omicron Pi Documents (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Chi Gamma Documents (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kappa Alpha Theta Documents, 1960s, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Delta Delta Delta Documents (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chi Omega Documents (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sigma Delta Tau Documents (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Delta Phi Epsilon Documents (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pi Beta Phi Documents (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kappa Kappa Gamma Documents (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Alpha Phi Documents (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Delta Gamma Documents (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Constitution and By-Laws of Sigma Kappa Sorority, July 8, 1952, July 8, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Sigma Kappa Documents, Late 1950s, Late 1950s (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Sigma Kappa, 1950s; Contains assorted documents, correspondence, newspaper articles, etc. focusing on the admission into the sorority of an African American student and the resulting fall-out with the national branch. (Box 3, Volume 2)
  - Housemother Manuals
    - "Handbook for Housemother or Chaperone," Alpha Phi Fraternity, 1947, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "Housemother's Manual," Alpha Omicron Pi, 1954; Financial Statement - Epsilon Chapter, June 1946, 1946, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - "Housemother's Manual," Alpha Epsilon Phi (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - "The College Housemother," 1964, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "Manual for Pi Beta Phi Chaperons," 1953, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "Housemother's Manual," Sigma Delta Tau, 1954, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - "Chi Gamma Housemother's Manual" (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - "Delta Delta Delta Manual for House Directors," 1950, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "Our Housemother," Delta Gamma, 1947, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Housemother's Handbook," Kappa Alpha Theta (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - "Cornell University Handbook for Sorority Head Residents," 1949, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Series II. General Panhellenic Council Papers
  - Sorority General Information, 1940s-1967, 1940s-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sorority Questionnaires and Statistics from Other Schools, 1950s-1960s, 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - National Panhellenic Conference, Information and Correspondence, 1950s-1960s, 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Panhellenic Adhoc Committee, New Sorority Study, 1959-1960, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Society Annual Reports, 1959-1964, 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - City of Ithaca Panhellenic, 1960s, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Sorority General Information, 1940s-1967, 1940s-1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Summary of Sorority Averages, 1961-1962, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Panhellenic Frosh Council Questionnaire on Rushing, 1962, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Report on Panhellenic Rushing Questionnaire, 1963-1964, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Panhellenic Rushing, Pre-1964, Pre-1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Panhellenic Rushing, 1964-1965, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Panhellenic Council, 1967-1968, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Panhellenic Computer Bill, 1968, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Sorority Financial Reports, 1968-1969, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Panhellenic Council, 1968-1969, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Panhellenic Council, 1969-1970, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Documents on Panhellenic Discrimination (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Role of National Organizations (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Pledge Training (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Panhellenic Rules (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Assorted Panhellenic Council Papers, 1940-1950, 1940-1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Assorted Panhellenic Council Papers, 1940-1950, 1940-1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Assorted Panhellenic Council Documents, 1940-1960, 1940-1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Panhellenic Notes, 1943-1948, 1943-1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Panhellenic Discrimination, 1950s-1960s, 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Rushing Documents, 1950s-1960s, 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Assorted Administrative and Rushing Documents, 1950s-1960s, 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Rushing Material, 1960s, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Handbook for City Panhellenics, 1961, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Panhellenic Rushing, 1965-1966, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Panhellenic Rushing, 1966-1967, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Panhellenic Rushing, 1967-1968, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Panhellenic National Notes (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Rushing, Historical (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Descriptions of the Ten Sororities (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Head Resident for Sororities Application Form (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Newspaper Articles About Sororities, September 1956-January 1957, September 1956-January 1957 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Cornell University: Sorority House President's Manual, 1960s; Includes information on policies, information on all the houses, some fraternities as well as sororities, including their academic averages, initiation and pledge costs, fees, and activities they participate in or organize on the campus and national level. Also a long list of frequently asked questions by rushees and the Constitution of the Cornell Panhellenic. (Box 3, Volume 1)
  - Sorority Statistics, 1960s; Information on academics, rushing, housing, membership, demographics, etc. (Box 3, Volume 3)
  - Rush Council, Panhellenic Council: Minutes for Present and Previous Year, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Volume 4)
  - Sorority Minutes, 1955-1963; Includes Panhellenic Council and Rushing Council minutes covering policies, rushing, infractions, etc. (Box 3, Volume 5)